By the end of the 19th centuries,
physicists
believed that they have basically found
out
everything about physics. Newton explained
motion.
We found out about electricity and
magnetism,
and thermodynamics explained heat. But
experiments
completely shattered what we know about
physics,
and that's when modern physics come into
play.
Modern physics is when energy stops being
continuous.
And we find out that energy is discrete or
quantized.
So first of all, let's start with
blackbody.
Blackbody radiation. So what is blackbody
radiation?
Blackbody is an object that both absorbs
and
emits electromagnetic radiation.
This can include infrared radiation.
Ultraviolet. Visible light.
Basically, everything on the
electromagnetic
spectrum, which is any type of energy
there
is. And physicists have experimentally
measured
how much energy is emitted at each
wavelength.
So, for example, let's say we have an atom
over
here. And this atom has shells.
Let's say this is the first shell, this is
the
second shell, or energy levels.
So this would be n equals one, and this
would
be n equals two. And n usually represents
the
energy level, or the shell. And in
chemistry,
this would be the valence shell. So this
one
would carry two electrons, eight, eight,
eight,
blah, blah, blah. So let's say we have a
hydrogen
atom over here, and it has one electron.
However, if we shine, or if we put energy
to
it at a specific wavelength, let's say we
put
some energy here, or shine a photon here,
it's
going to excite this electron, and this
electron
is going to jump up. And that's absorption
of
energy. It absorbs the energy of the
photon
we shine through, making it jump up to a
higher
energy. And over time, this excited
electron
will go down, go back down in different
steps.
For example, it might take this route, or
it
goes down one by one, or it can jump all
the
way back down again, back to its original
state,
otherwise known as the ground level. And
that
is when it emits energy.
Now, two main things you have to know
about
energy is, energy is in photons, and
this can result in photons with a
different
frequency, and photons with a different
wavelength.
Now, what is the difference? Well,
frequency
and wavelength are inversely proportional.
So, if the frequency increases, that means
that
you would have a lower wavelength, and if
you
have a higher wavelength, then frequency
decreases.
And frequency is the amount of
oscillations,
or the amount of up and downs, a photon
goes
through in one second. Wavelength is just
the
length between each thing, so it would
make
sense if the frequency was bigger, then
the
wavelength would be smaller. A higher
frequency
means that it's going up and down more
quickly,
and a higher frequency would indicate more
energy.
The energy formula is given by E equals hc
over
lambda, and this is a relatively important
formula
that you have to know. And this h is
Planck's
constant, c is the speed of light, and
lambda
is the wavelength. So, that's that.
And that's just a really brief
introduction
about modern physics. Next video, we'll
learn
how each sublevel, or the jumping of each
sublevel,
requires different amount of energy, and
how
it eventually converges to infinity.
See you, and thanks for watching!